---missing---
// what  my project / plan / goal is
---missing---

Day 1 - 14.03.19
I'm trying to realize a project that requires simple code based procedural generation of 3d Objects, animating them including complex behavior and physically calculated interaction with the environment. This should all happen without opening any other program, and most certainly not pasting code into a complex program like blender.
The reason I wrote that last sentence down, is because from the moment of the conception of this project on, I always planned to use blender for something like this. Just today (14.03.19) though I found out that this is not done as simply as adding bpy to your python path, importing it into a script and running it. I expected to be able to fully build a scene, with animation, physics and scripted behavior.
Now that I'm typing this out, it seems a bit ridiculous, but for some reason I was always convinced that this would work very nicely, thinking I have researched this project enough. The reality of it seems to be though, that for python scripts to work in blender, they need to be run through blenders very own python interpreter, which is directly built into blender, which apparently can't be accessed through a terminal that gets initiated through, and takes inputs from a python file. There seem to be a number of workarounds / solutions for this problem though, one which even includes a python module [https://pypi.org/project/bpy/].
Though I have been able to fully render a blender scene through cd'ing to blenders location and executing a cmd command there [https://docs.blender.org/manual/en/latest/render/workflows/command_line.html], and get its output png, I don't know how to give it the instructions for generating and even interactively rendering a physics based 3d scene.
So while I'm definitely still trying to figure out if it can be done through blender, I'm also trying to look into other alternatives such as OpenGL, pi3d, Panda3D, vpython, vispy, (probably not:) matplotlib3d.
But even instead looking into these things, for some weird reason I decided to start writing this text maybe as some kind of starting point for a future blog? Also just because I really wanna push something to GitHub. Oh and I should learn how to use git. And study Chinese. And...

Day 2 - 18.03.2019
For now I've decided on using Panda3D for this Project. I'm trying to figure out how to use it, and decide whether it is appropriate for this project. Right now I'm working myself through this guide on their website: [https://www.panda3d.org/manual/].

After having completed the first tutorial, by basically just copying the instructions given on the website, I still feel like I can't say much about the intricacies of panda3d, but I have observed that there is lots to discover here.

This module has lots of custom built-in features like Intervals and Sequences used for modifying position and rotation in a 3d space. There's also some kind of task manager, and a bunch of other stuff that falls out of the programming paradigms I've learned so far in python.

My next goal will be to simply generate a cube using only code, i.e. not importing a 3d model, so I can eventually move on to procedural generation, which is kind of the whole point of this exercise! However it seems as though I first have to sift through several pages of what seems like decent documentation, however it is still a tedious task.
Let's see if my absolutely laughable foundation of how vertices, edges, faces, normal and so work, that I have gathered through blender and unity3d, will do me any good. [https://www.panda3d.org/manual/?title=GeomVertexData]

//what I understand so far:
Objects are naturally defined through their vertices (3d points).
These vertices can also contain more data than just their position in panda 3d (e.g. normal, color, texture coordinates ...).
The information about each vertex is stored in a row in the GeomVertexData Object, wherein each column represents a different data to be described (position, normal and so on). The data we want to input into GeomVertexData is inserted via writer, objects which we also first have to initialize for each GeomVertexData set.

The structure of this GeomVertexData object is defined within a GeomVertexFormat object, which is linked to GeomVertexData.
The vertices and their corresponding data are then indexed (called) through GeomPrimitives, thus putting them into the correct order to draw different kinds of primitive shapes.
These shapes are pre-defined:
1 GeomTriangles
2 GeomTristrips
3 GeomTrifans
4 GeomLines
5 GeomLinestrips
6 GeomPoints

Those shapes are nicely described here: [https://www.panda3d.org/manual/?title=GeomPrimitive]
Just one thing to add: They are subcategorized into 1-3: Triangles, 4-5: Lines, 6: Points

GeomVertexData and GeomVertexPrimitive are tied together by Geoms. They are made of GeomPrimitives, describe complex geometries, and are directly attached to the rendered scene. As before, these are also only pointers, taking information from the previously mentioned sources.

A Geom can either be rendered, or not. There is no in-between state. While a Geom can consist of as many Primitives as you want, these primitives have to be of the same type: triangle, line or point!

Moving up one layer, we now have GeomNodes. They contain an array of Geoms and their respective render states. GeomNodes are directly placed in the scene graph, and can inherit from its parents in the scene graph (I really don’t understand what I’m typing here...).

Bounding volumes... Think colliders in unity3d. They are generated automatically.

The first step to creating any geometry in panda is specifying a GeomVertexFormat.
First an empty panda-internal array (GeomVertexArrayFormat()) is assigned to a variable.
To my current understanding, this variable only really represents a single row in GeomVertexFormat, so all the columns that are then added are also only one-dimensional (Again, these are just my assumptions!!!). Using a method, you give each column parameters to define what data is stored in there.

These arrays / rows / GeomVertexArrayFormat are then added to a GeomVertexFormat () object, also of course stored in a variable. The format has to be registered, using the .registerFormat(format) method, however this should be done by assigning the return value of this method to the GeomVertexFormat object it was applied to, because the unregistered GeomVertexFormat should not be kept. Of course this can be done in other ways, it is just important, that the old object should be discarded.


//p3d documentation kinda sucks atm 

Day 4 – 20.3.2019
Actually worked on the problem yesterday too, which is why this is day 3. I worked myself through lots of documentation, which happens to be in a process of reorganization at the time of writing this. This made things kind of disorganized, also the existing documentation on procedurally generating 3d Objects is lacking, I find. It never mentioned in which class any of the methods were situated, so I first used the github repo to search through the frameworks folders to figure it out. I later found this helpful list of all the classes on the website: [https://www.panda3d.org/reference/python/annotated.html]. Most of the stuff I needed was nested in the panda3d.core directory so that helped me a bunch.

The other major roadblock was figuring out why I couldn’t place nodes in the root of panda scene graph (I’ll have to explain the scene graph and node system some other time). The reason was, that I did not call the direct.showbase.ShowBase() class first, which also creates the scene graph (and loads of other stuff). Only then I was able to insert my triangles node into the root of the tree.

But when it all worked out (after I added normals and color to my vertices, and also moved my view to the correct position), I saw the most glorious blue triangle rendered on my Screen. That was a happy moment!
